Frank A. Johnson Papers
Frank A. Johnson Papers
1889-1965
Johnson, Frank A., 1908-
25 linear ft.
Papers of the American business executive, President of Endicott-Johnson Corporation. Correspondence (1957-1963); personnel material (1926-1965); business records (1889-1965); clippings, and photographs. Personnel material includes correspondence, manuscripts, reports, and published material relating to employees of Endicott-Johnson Corporation; production records include correspondence, manuscripts, reports, blueprints, sketches, and financial reports of the shoe manufacturer.
149087
Biographical History
Frank A. Johnson was born in Endicott, New York on December 6, 1908. He was the son of George W. and Lulu (Seagers) Johnson. From 1927 to 1930 he attended the Hill School at Pottstown, Pennsylvania.
In keeping with the policy of his grandfather, George F. Johnson, Frank Johnson learned the shoe business by starting "at the bottom." In 1931 he was hired as a worker in the Endicott-Johnson Corporation, and in 1938 he became a superintendent of one of the factories. He was elected a member of the Board of Directors in 1946, and made vice-president of the company in 1948. He succeeded his second cousin, Charles F. Johnson, Jr. to the presidency in 1957.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Frank A. Johnson Papers include correspondence, manuscripts, reports and published material. The collection is divided into five series.
Correspondence (1957-1963) contains the incoming correspondence of Frank A. Johnson. Subject files (1924-1963) includes correspondence, photos, reports, and published material. Personnel (1926-1965) includes correspondence, manuscripts, reports, and published material relating to employment and employee benefits and programs, and contains newspaper clippings of the Binghamton Sun's Workers Pages arranged chronologically.
Production (1889-1965) is divided into two parts: Related materials and Business transactions. Related material contains correspondence, manuscripts, reports, blueprints, sketches and published material pertaining to shoe manufacturing. It also includes sections on finance and publicity. Business transactions includes correspondence, reports and printed material concerning the different companies with which Endicott-Johnson had business dealings.
Published material (1956-1960) contains newspaper clippings.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by sender, the outgoing correspondence arranged chronologically and correspondence of others arranged alphabetically by name.
Within Production files, Related material is arranged alphabetically by subject and type and Business transactions are arranged arranged alphabetically by company name.
Subject files, Personnel, and Published material are arranged alphabetically by subject.
Subject and Genre Headings
Business and Industry; New York State; Johnson, Frank A., 1908-; Endicott-Johnson Corporation -- Employees.; Endicott-Johnson Corporation -- History -- Sources.; Executives -- New York (State); Footwear industry -- New York (State); Industrial relations -- United States.; Shoe industry -- Employees.; Shoe industry -- New York (State); Manufactures -- United States.; Endicott (N.Y.) -- Industries.; Blueprints (reprographic copies); Business records.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Financial records.; Manuscripts (document genre); Personnel records.; Photographs.; Reports.; Sketches.; Chief executive officers.; Executives.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Incoming
    - A-B, 1957-1963 (Box 1)
    - C-G, 1956-1961 (Box 1)
    - H, J-M, 1957-1963 (Box 1)
    - N-P, R-S, 1957-1961 (Box 1)
    - T-W, Y, 1957-1963 (Box 1)
    - McLaughlin, Betty, 1961 (Box 1)
    - Unidentified, 1957-1958; undated (Box 1)
  - Outgoing
    - 1947-1949, 1951-1953, 1955-1957 (Box 1)
    - 1958-1965 (Box 1)
  - Of others
    - of Endicott-Johnson Corporation, 1930; 1955,; 1963-1964 (Box 1)
    - Hagan, William, 1930 (Box 1)
    - Johnson, Charles F., 1948-1950 (Box 1)
    - Johnson, George W., 1934 (Box 1)
    - Steed, Leonard, 1946; 1950,; 1953,; undated (Box 1)
- Subject files
  - Binghamton "Triplets" Baseball Club, 1930; 1958 (Box 2)
  - Church of the Nazarene, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Cornell University Seminars, 1957-1958 (Box 2)
  - Endicott-Johnson "Management News", undated; Proposal (Box 2)
  - Invitations, 1957-1962 (Box 2)
  - Johnson City Real Estate Development, undated (Box 2)
  - Johnson City 60th Anniversary Celebration, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Lists of names, undated (Box 2)
  - Luria Dismantling Project, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Memos, 1957-1958 (Box 2)
  - New York State Solid Fuels Administration Report, undated (Box 2)
  - Pamphlets, 1943; 1947,; 1956,; undated (Box 2)
  - Photos
    - 1924, 1948, 1950, undated (Box 2)
    - Johnson, Frank A. and Swazye, John Cameron autographed, 1960 (Oversize 1)
  - School centralization, 1959 (Box 2)
  - Scrap Mobilization Committee, 1951-1952 (Box 2)
  - Tribute to George F. Johnson, 1959; undated (Box 2)
  - United Engineers and Constructors, Inc., 1953; 1956-1957,; 1959; 1960-1963 (Box 2)
  - Valley Economic Development Association, 1957; 1959,; undated (Box 2)
- Personnel
  - Absenteeism, 1961; undated (Box 3)
  - Accidents, 1946-1949; 1951-1960,; undated (Box 3)
  - Acqua Tera Sportsman's Club, 1954 (Box 3)
  - American Legion, 1949 (Box 3)
  - Banquets, 1956; 1957 (Box 3)
  - Benefits
    - Bonuses, 1926; 1948-1959 (Box 3)
    - Bowling program, 1950; 1957-1961,; undated (Box 3)
    - Company housing
      - Binghamton Savings Bank, 1956-1960 (Box 3)
      - Cases
        - 1947-1953 (Box 3)
        - 1954-1963, undated (Box 3)
      - Deyo Hill Tract reports, 1954; 1957-1958,; 1960,; 1962 (Box 3)
      - Reports and policy, 1936-1937; 1947-1954,; undated (Box 4)
      - 1955-1961, undated (Box 4)
      - Workers home visits, 1954-1958; undated (Box 4)
    - Company loans
      - 1942, 1945-1952 (Box 4)
      - 1953-1961, undated (Box 4)
    - Cut backs, 1960-1961 (Box 4)
    - Death, 1947-1948; 1950-1964 (Box 4)
    - Endicott-Johnson Athletic Association, 1930; 1947-1961 (Box 4)
    - En-Joie Golf Club, 1957-1961; undated (Box 4)
    - Equitable Life Insurance Society of the United States, 1961-1962; Miller, Mason & Dickenson,Inc. (Box 4)
    - George F. Pavilion Recreation Center
      - 1950-1956 (Box 4)
      - Public market, 1958; undated (Box 4)
    - Holidays with pay, 1941; 1944,; 1956-1958,; 1961 (Box 4)
    - Medical
      - Blue Cross/Blue Shield plans, 1958-1962 (Box 5)
      - Cases
        - 1930, 1943-1950 (Box 5)
        - 1951-1955 (Box 5)
        - 1956-1959 (Box 5)
        - 1960-1961 (Box 5)
        - 1962-1965, undated (Box 5)
      - Clinical reports
        - 1949, 1953-1955 (Box 6)
        - 1956-1957 (Box 6)
        - 1958-1960 (Box 6)
        - 1961-1962 (Box 6)
        - 1963, undated (Box 6)
      - Klimow, Dr. Nicholas I., 1950 (Box 6)
      - Policy and reports
        - 1932, 1943-1957, undated (Box 6)
        - 1958-1960, undated (Box 6)
        - 1961-1963, undated (Box 7)
      - Wilson Memorial Hospital, 1950; 1959-1963 (Box 7)
      - Workmen's Compensation policy, 1949; 1955-1962,; undated (Box 7)
    - Pension and retirement
      - Cases, 1943-1963; undated (Box 7)
      - Policy, 1946-1954 (Box 7)
    - Profit sharing plan and common stock, 1918; 1921 (Box 7)
    - Reports, 1960; undated (Box 7)
    - Seniority, 1948-1950; 1953,; 1957-1959,; 1961-1964 (Box 7)
    - Thirty-Year Club
      - 1942, 1947-1949, 1951, 1957-1963, undated (Box 7)
      - Speeches, 1959-1960 (Box 7)
    - Vacations, 1944; 1947-1964,; undated (Box 8)
    - Workers recreational center
      - 1948-1960, undated (Box 8)
      - Furnishing, 1948-1950 (Box 8)
  - Board of directors, 1945 (Box 8)
  - Brainstorming sessions, undated (Box 8)
  - Breakage and damages, 1954-1955 (Box 8)
  - Deaths and funerals, 1952-1961; undated (Box 8)
  - Eckelberger, Robert, 1943; 1956 (Box 8)
  - 8-Hour Day Celebration pamphlet, undated (Box 8)
  - Employee
    - Handbook, 1958-1959; 1962,; undated (Box 8)
    - Problems, 1943; 1946,; 1954-1963 (Box 8)
    - Suggestions
      - 1930, 1938-1939, 1941, 1945, 1947-1949, 1952-1957, undated (Box 8)
      - 1958-1959 (Box 8)
      - 1960-1962, 1954-1965, undated (Box 9)
      - Reports, 1948; 1958-1959,; undated (Box 9)
    - Training
      - 1930, 1951-1956, 1960 (Box 9)
      - Cornell University, 1958 (Box 9)
  - Employment
    - Hungarian, 1954; 1956-1957,; undated (Box 9)
    - Records, 1949-1950; 1952,; 1955,; 1957-1960,; undated (Box 9)
    - Statistics, 1942; 1948-1950 (Box 9)
  - Endicott-Johnson Contributor, undated; layout (Box 9)
  - Endicott-Johnson News, 1960; 2 mimeographed copies (Box 9)
  - 50th Golden Jubilee year
    - Johnson, Charles F., 1955 (Box 9)
    - Workers with 50 years service, 1955 (Box 9)
  - Forman Training Program, 1955; 1956,; 1959,; undated (Box 9)
  - Forms, 1952 (Box 9)
  - Grievances
    - Machine repair and service maintenance, 1962; undated (Box 9)
    - Management, 1947-1964; undated (Box 9)
    - Petition, 1947 (Box 9)
    - Salary, 1946-1964 (Box 9)
  - Inquiries, 1930; 1945,; 1947,; 1956-1962; re employees (Box 10)
  - Invitations, 1948-1949; 1952,; 1958,; 1960-1961 (Box 10)
  - Job
    - Applications
      - 1930, 1946-1957, undated (Box 10)
      - 1958-1959 (Box 10)
      - 1960-1965, undated (Box 10)
    - Descriptions, 1958; 1961,; undated (Box 10)
  - Johnson, Harry L., 1958; undated (Box 10)
  - Jury duty, 1953; 1956,; 1957,; 1959,; undated (Box 10)
  - Labor arbitration
    - Copeloff, Maxwell, 1942-1945 (Box 10)
    - Lappin, A. C., 1943 (Box 10)
    - Submissions to arbitrate, 1943-1945 (Box 10)
  - Lay-offs and dismissals, 1948-1950; 1952,; 1954,; 1957-1965 (Box 10)
  - Leaves of absence, 1943; 1945-1958,; 1961 (Box 11)
  - Legal, 1945-1958; 1960,; 1962,; 1965 (Box 11)
  - Letters
    - From workers
      - 1947, 1950-1957 (Box 11)
      - 1958-1963, undated (Box 11)
    - To workers, 1953; 1957-1964 (Box 11)
    - Recommendations, 1930; 1944-1945,; 1951-1964 (Box 11)
  - Liberty Mutual Insurance Co., 1948; undated (Box 11)
  - Lumber and leather purchases, 1946-1949 (Box 11)
  - Manpower, 1960-1961 (Box 11)
  - Manufacturing division, 1960-1961 (Box 11)
  - Memos and notes, 1947; 1949,; 1957-1959,; undated (Box 11)
  - Men In Service Dept, 1948-1949; 1956-1957,; 1965,; undated; Veterans, G. I.'s and reserves (Box 11)
  - Mills, Raymond, 1957; 1959,; 1960-1961 (Box 11)
  - Notices to workers
    - Drafts, 1961; 1962,; undated (Box 12)
    - 1921, 1933, 1934, 1938, 1940-1946 (Box 12)
    - 1947-1950 (Box 12)
    - 1951-1964, undated (Box 12)
    - Holidays
      - 1939, 1941-1952 (Box 12)
      - 1953-1963, undated (Box 12)
  - Notices to supervisors, superintendents and foremen
    - 1931-1942 (Box 13)
    - 1945-1950 (Box 13)
    - 1951-1963 (Box 13)
    - Notebook
      - 1945-1949 (Box 13)
      - 1951-1956, 1960 (Box 13)
  - Office memos, 1946 (Box 14)
  - Parking problems, 1947; 1962 (Box 14)
  - Part-time workers, 1950; 1951,; 1954,; 1958,; 1963 (Box 14)
  - Payroll
    - 1942-1946 (Box 14)
    - 1947-1956, 1964 (Box 14)
    - Policy, 1941; 1947,; 1954,; undated (Box 14)
    - Reports and surveys, 1943-1954; undated (Box 14)
    - Wage increases and reductions, 1939-1951; 1953,; 1957 (Box 14)
  - Petitions, 1947; undated (Box 14)
  - Promotions, 1958-1961; undated (Box 14)
  - Rehiring, 1945-1952; 1956-1963 (Box 14)
  - Reinstatement, 1943-1949; 1953-1964 (Box 14)
  - Releases and statements of availability, 1943 (Box 14)
  - Relief office, 1951-1960 (Box 14)
  - Resignations, 1947; 1959-1962,; 1964 (Box 14)
  - Reports and surveys, 1956; 1960-1961,; undated (Box 14)
  - Retired workers dinners
    - 1948-1952, 1958 (Box 15)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 15)
    - Speeches
      - 1959 (Box 15)
      - 1960 (Box 15)
  - Service dept., 1949 (Box 15)
  - Sheltered workshop, 1947; 1949,; 1957 (Box 15)
  - Special, 1947-1952; undated; Gervais, Al and Uveges, Michael (Box 15)
  - Statement of policy on conflict of interest
    - Signed acknowledgements A-W, 1961 (Box 15)
    - Drafts, 1961-1964 (Box 15)
    - List of employees, undated; re purchasing (Box 15)
    - Questionnaire for officers and directors, 1960-1962 (Box 15)
  - Stockholders, 1961-1964 (Box 15)
  - Subsidey program, 1958; 1961 (Box 15)
  - Sweet, Guy, 1930 (Box 15)
  - 30, 40, 50 year workers, 1958-1959; 1963 (Box 15)
  - Timing manual, 1959; 1961 (Box 15)
  - Transfers, 1945-1950; 1952-1964 (Box 15)
  - Unemployment insurance, 1961; 1962 (Box 15)
  - Unionization, 1938-1940; 1945-1949,; 1956-1963,; undated (Box 15)
  - Wilcox, Norton, 1948-1963 (Box 15)
  - Workers
    - Band, 1960 (Box 15)
    - Chorus, 1946; 1948,; 1952-1963,; undated (Box 15)
    - Page correspondence, 1949; 1954-1960,; undated (Box 15)
  - Workers pages
    - 1957, January (Box 16)
    - 1957, February (Box 16)
    - 1957, May (Box 16)
    - 1957, June (Box 16)
    - 1957, July (Box 16)
    - 1957, August (Box 16)
    - 1957, September (Box 16)
    - 1957, October (Box 17)
    - 1957, November (Box 17)
    - 1957, December (Box 17)
    - 1958, January (Box 17)
    - 1958, February (Box 17)
    - 1958, March (Box 17)
    - 1958, April (Box 17)
    - 1958, May (Box 17)
    - 1958, June (Box 17)
    - 1958, July (Box 17)
    - 1958, August (Box 17)
    - 1958, September (Box 18)
    - 1958, October (Box 18)
    - 1958, November (Box 18)
    - 1958, December (Box 18)
    - 1959, January (Box 18)
    - 1959, February (Box 18)
    - 1959, March (Box 18)
    - 1959, April (Box 18)
    - 1959, May (Box 18)
    - 1959, June (Box 18)
    - 1959, July (Box 18)
    - 1959, August (Box 19)
    - 1959, September (Box 19)
    - 1959, October (Box 19)
    - 1959, November (Box 19)
    - 1959, December (Box 19)
    - 1960, January (Box 19)
    - 1960, February (Box 19)
    - 1960, March (Box 19)
    - 1960, April (Box 19)
    - 1960, May (Box 19)
    - 1960, June (Box 19)
    - 1960, July (Box 19)
    - 1960, August (Box 19)
    - 1960, September (Box 20)
    - 1960, October (Box 20)
    - 1960, November (Box 20)
    - 1960, December (Box 20)
    - 1961, January (Box 20)
    - 1961, February (Box 20)
    - 1961, March (Box 20)
    - 1961, April (Box 20)
    - 1961, May (Box 20)
    - 1961, June (Box 20)
    - 1961, July (Box 20)
    - 1961, August (Box 20)
    - 1961, September (Box 20)
    - 1961, October (Box 20)
    - 1961, November (Box 20)
    - 1961, December (Box 20)
    - 1962, January (Box 20)
    - 1962, February (Box 20)
    - 1962, March (Box 20)
    - 1962, April (Box 20)
    - 1962, May (Box 20)
    - 1962, June (Box 20)
    - 1962, July (Box 20)
    - 1962, August (Box 20)
    - 1962, September (Box 20)
    - 1962, October (Box 21)
    - 1962, November (Box 21)
    - 1962, December (Box 21)
    - 1963, January (Box 21)
    - 1963, February (Box 21)
    - 1963, March (Box 21)
    - 1963, April (Box 21)
    - 1963, May (Box 21)
    - 1963, June (Box 21)
    - 1963, July (Box 21)
    - 1963, August (Box 21)
    - 1963, September (Box 21)
    - 1963, October (Box 21)
    - 1963, November (Box 21)
    - 1963, December (Box 21)
    - 1964, January (Box 21)
    - 1964, February (Box 21)
    - 1964, March (Box 21)
    - 1964, April (Box 21)
    - 1964, May (Box 21)
    - 1964, June (Box 21)
    - 1964, July (Box 21)
    - 1964, August (Box 21)
    - 1964, September (Box 21)
    - 1964, October (Box 21)
    - 1964, November (Box 21)
    - 1964, December (Box 21)
    - 1965, January (Box 21)
    - 1965, February (Box 21)
    - 1965, March (Box 21)
    - 1965, April (Box 21)
    - 1965, May (Box 21)
    - 1965, June (Box 21)
    - 1965, July (Box 21)
    - 1965, August (Box 21)
    - 1965, September (Box 21)
    - 1965, October (Box 21)
    - 1965, November (Box 21)
    - 1965, December (Box 21)
- Production
  - Related material
    - Advertising other companies, 1930; 1945,; 1952,; 1955,; 1961 (Box 22)
    - Brainstorming sessions, 1958 (Box 22)
    - Consumer problems, 1946; 1949,; 1953-1956,; 1959,; 1961-1963,; undated (Box 22)
    - Departments
      - Carton, 1930; 1949,; 1952-1957 (Box 22)
      - Engineering, 1958 (Box 22)
      - Fire prevention, 1946-1947; 1952,; 1957,; 1961,; undated (Box 22)
      - Marketing division, 1960 (Box 22)
      - Property, 1953-1958; undated (Box 22)
      - Purchasing, 1949; 1952-1958,; undated (Box 22)
      - Retail stores, 1930 (Box 22)
      - Rubber canvas footwear terminal, 1957-1958 (Box 22)
      - Service, 1948; 1952-1953 (Box 22)
      - Tag, 1954-1958 (Box 22)
      - Upper leather, 1947; 1953,; 1956-1957,; undated (Box 22)
    - Factories
      - All sports, 1941; 1952-1956 (Box 22)
      - Binghamton Busy Boys, 1937; 1949,; 1952-1956 (Box 22)
      - Binghamton Workshoe, 1943; 1953,; 1955-1956 (Box 22)
      - Boys and youths, 1947; 1948,; 1952-1956,; 1958,; undated (Box 22)
      - Challenge, 1952-1953 (Box 22)
      - Corliss Fibre and Counterboard Mill, 1952-1958 (Box 22)
      - Fair Play, 1954 (Box 22)
      - Fine McKay, 1952-1958; undated (Box 22)
      - General operations, 1943-1949; 1953,; 1956,; undated (Box 22)
      - George F., 1951-1953; 1956-1958,; undated (Box 23)
      - Infants, 1947; 1952-1958 (Box 23)
      - Jigger, 1947; 1952-1953,; 1956-1957 (Box 23)
      - Juvenile, 1952-1953; 1956,; 1958 (Box 23)
      - Medium McKay, 1930; 1952-1954,; 1956,; 1958,; undated (Box 23)
      - Misses and children, 1952; 1953,; 1958,; undated (Box 23)
      - Paracord, 1948; 1951-1958 (Box 23)
      - Pioneer, 1946-1948; 1952,; 1953,; 1956,; undated (Box 23)
      - Scout, 1945; 1948,; 1952-1953,; 1957-1958,; 1962 (Box 23)
      - Sunrise, 1952-1958; undated (Box 23)
      - Victory, 1952-1956 (Box 23)
      - Visitors, 1941; 1945,; 1948-1952,; 1954-1963,; undated (Box 23)
    - Finance
      - Babcock, Robert fiscal comparisons, 1957 (Box 23)
      - Stanford, Linda
        - Biographical, 1962; undated (Box 23)
        - Auditors Touche, Ross, Bailey & Smart, 1960-1961 (Box 23)
        - Inventory positions, 1960-1962; undated (Box 23)
        - Progress reports, 1959; 1960-1961 (Box 23)
        - Reports and surveys
          - 1954, 1956-1959, undated (Box 24)
          - 1960, undated (Box 24)
          - 1961 (Box 24)
    - Golf ball plant, 1938; 1947 (Box 24)
    - Government contracts
      - Boots, 1945; undated (Box 24)
      - Hospital slippers, 1952 (Box 24)
    - Heels, 1930; 1946-1949,; 1951-1952,; 1956,; 1958; Inquiries (Box 24)
    - Ideas and inventions
      - 1945-1951, 1954-1956 (Box 24)
      - 1957-1963, undated (Box 24)
    - Lackawanna Industrial Fund Enterprises, 1959 (Box 24)
    - Lasts, 1946-1949; 1951,; 1961,; undated; Inquiries (Box 24)
    - Machinery, 1945; 1946,; 1947,; 1950-1953 (Box 24)
    - Motivational research
      - Institute for Motivational Research, Inc., 1959-1960; including correspondence with Dr. Ernest Dichter (Box 25)
      - Motivation Dynamics, Inc. Shepard, Albert, 1960; undated (Box 25)
      - "The Signifigance of the Endicott Johnson Name to Independent Retailers and to Consumers", 1961; submitted by Motivation Dynamics, Inc. (Box 25)
    - Notices
      - Re rationing of footwear, 1942-1943 (Box 25)
      - To supervisors, superintendents and foremen
        - 1928-1939 (Box 25)
        - 1940-1943 (Box 25)
        - 1945-1948 (Box 25)
        - 1949-1950 (Box 25)
        - 1951-1953 (Box 25)
        - 1954-1963 (Box 25)
    - Office of Price Administration, 1944 (Box 25)
    - Patents
      - Affadavit Shultz, Edward, 1955 (Box 26)
      - Assorted, 1889-1957 (Box 26)
      - CEMA process, 1953; 1957-1958 (Box 26)
      - Daniels Perforated Shoe, 1939-1941 (Box 26)
      - Dies
        - Assorted, 1889-1950 (Box 26)
        - Homberg, Hans, 1957; 1958 (Box 26)
        - Ontario Die Co. Ltd., 1945; 1947 (Box 26)
        - Rylander, Berhhard Uno, 1951; 1955 (Box 26)
      - Goodyear Stitching Machines, 1936; undated (Box 26)
      - Infringement
        - 1935, 1947-1949, 1954, 1956 (Box 26)
        - Plastic heel base, 1960 (Box 26)
      - Johnson, Frank A., 1945-1946 (Box 26)
      - Lease and license agreements, 1933; 1936,; 1946-1947 (Box 26)
      - Memos, 1956 (Box 26)
      - Notice of allowance, 1936 (Box 26)
      - Requests to manufacture, 1934-1936; 1947-1949,; 1953-1961 (Box 26)
      - Searches, 1947-1949 (Box 26)
      - Steed, Leonard L., 1930; 1944-1945,; 1947,; 1949 (Box 26)
    - Permacounter
      - Bennett Ltd., 1952-1959 (Box 26)
      - Brockton Cut Sole Corp., 1954-1959 (Box 26)
      - Ciaio, Frank, 1954; 1958,; 1960 (Box 26)
      - Contracts, 1949-1962; undated (Box 27)
      - Development
        - 1946, 1949-1953, undated (Box 27)
        - 1954-1956 (Box 27)
        - E. I. DuPont DeNemours & Co., 1954; 1956 (Box 27)
        - The Fellows Gear Shaper Co., 1954-1955 (Box 27)
        - Lester-Phoenix, Inc., 1952-1953 (Box 27)
        - Newarak Die Co., Inc., 1953-1958 (Box 27)
        - Standard Tool Co., 1950-1959 (Box 27)
      - Grant Plastics, Inc., 1951-1952 (Box 27)
      - Interested concerns
        - A-L, 1949-1958 (Box 27)
        - M-W, 1949-1958 (Box 27)
      - Lab reports, 1950-1957; undated (Box 27)
      - Legal
        - 1950-1955 (Box 27)
        - 1956-1962 (Box 28)
      - Patents
        - Colella, G. S., 1955 (Box 28)
        - Marcy, Robert J.
          - 1949-1955 (Box 28)
          - 1956-1963, undated (Box 28)
      - Reports and surveys
        - 1950-1956 (Box 28)
        - 1957-1963, undated (Box 28)
      - Rubber and Asbestos Corp., 1954-1957 (Box 28)
      - Sales -Roeder, Clarence, 1954-1956 (Box 28)
      - Union Carbide and Carbon Corp., 1950-1954; Bakelite Division (Box 28)
      - U. S. government bids, 1956 (Box 28)
      - Wright-Batchelder Corporation, 1951; 1953-1954,; undated (Box 28)
    - Plastic boot project, 1954-1955 (Box 28)
    - Plastic materials, 1946-1947; 1950,; 1957 (Box 28)
    - Polyethylene materials, 1955-1957 (Box 28)
    - Publicity
      - Correspondence, 1959; 1961,; 1964 (Box 28)
      - Endicott Johnson Press Luncheon, 1960 (Box 28)
      - Photos, undated (Box 28)
      - Selvage & Lee, Inc.
        - Clippings
          - October, November, 1959; April, 1960 (Box 29)
          - May 1-May 19, 1960 (Box 29)
          - May 20-May 30, 1960 (Box 29)
          - June, 1960 (Box 29)
          - July, 1960 (Box 29)
          - August, 1960 (Box 29)
          - September, 1960 (Box 29)
          - October, November, 1960; February, May, October, 1961, undated (Box 30)
        - News releases, 1959; 1960,; undated (Box 30)
      - WNBF radio and TV, 1957-1961; undated (Box 30)
    - Reymond System, 1940; 1945,; 1949 (Box 30)
    - Royalty, 1946; 1954,; 1960; comparative unit payments (Box 30)
    - Rubber Manufacturing Association, Inc.
      - Bulletins, 1940-1944; 1951,; 1959 (Box 30)
      - Correspondence, 1941-1942; 1944-1945,; 1950-1951,; 1955 (Box 30)
      - Newsletters, 1941-1943; 1945,; 1947,; 1949,; 1961,; undated (Box 30)
      - Reports
        - 1942, 1944, 1948-1949, 1952-1953 (Box 30)
        - 1954-1956 (Box 30)
    - Sales, 1939; 1942,; 1954,; 1957-1958,; 1960 (Box 30)
    - Shoe sketches, undated (Box 30)
    - Soles and soling material, 1944-1948; 1951; Inquiries (Box 30)
    - Thread, 1946-1948; 1953,; 1954,; undated (Box 30)
    - Trademarks, 1959; Infringement (Box 30)
    - Visits to other shoe manufacturers, 1948; 1949,; 1957-1958,; 1963 (Box 30)
    - Welting, 1954-1955 (Box 30)
  - Business transactions
    - Agoos Kid Ca, Inc., 1930 (Box 31)
    - Archbald Enterprise Association, 1946 (Box 31)
    - Arnott Shoe Co., 1947-1949; 1945 (Box 31)
    - Automation Consultants, 1960 (Box 31)